Zexy, Zany, Zensational!
Zorro, The Gay Blade is a western, action, comedy film directed by Peter Medak.
In 19th century Mexico, legendary swordsman Zorro has passed on his weapon and his sense
of duty to his noble son, Diego, a dashing swashbuckler like his father.
But after an injury sidelines Diego, he is forced to
hand the mask over to his twin, Ramon.
Don Diego Vega / Zorro / Bunny Wigglesworth / The Gay Blade
/ Ramon Vega, played by George Hamilton.
Charlotte Taylor Wilson, played by Lauren Hutton.
Florinda, played by Brenda Vaccaro.
Captain Esteban, played by Ron Leibman.
Paco, played by Donovan Scott.
Velasquez, played by James Booth.
Zorro, The Gay Blade is a 1981 American swashbuckling comedy
film from 20th Century Fox, produced by C.O.
Erickson and George Hamilton, directed by Peter Medak, that stars
Hamilton, Lauren Hutton, Ron Leibman, and Brenda Vaccaro.
The film's opening prologue states: "This film is dedicated to Rouben Mamoulian and the other great filmmakers whose past gives us our future."
The prologue quickly
establishes that Zorro, The Gay Blade is a tongue-in-cheek sequel to 20th Century Fox's swashbuckling adventure film The Mark of Zorro (1940), directed by Mamoulian.
Hamilton was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy at the 39th Golden Globe Awards for
playing the dual role of Don Diego de la Vega (Zorro) and his gay twin brother Bunny Wigglesworth, aka Ramón de la Vega.
The film explores themes of madrid, spain, sword fight, lgbt,
based on myths, legends or folklore, 19th century.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.